<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="taskId">
    <title>Transcribe Data</title>
    <shortdesc>Transcribe data from the media file.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>With the <wintitle>Media Player</wintitle> open, from the <wintitle>Record
                    Data</wintitle> view:</context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click on the play button to the left of the <i>Segment</i> tier
                        (<userinput>CMD/CTRL+R</userinput>) and type or use the <uicontrol>IPA
                        Map</uicontrol> to enter the utterance into the <i>Orthography</i> tier. </cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click on the <i>Orthography</i> tier and add word groups for each word by
                    clicking <uicontrol>New group after current</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>This will generate corresponding word groups in the <i>IPA Target</i>
                    and <i>IPA Actual </i> tiers as well as any other group-aligned
                    tiers.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>If you wish to use built-in dictionaries of pronounced forms, select the <menucascade>
                        <uicontrol>View</uicontrol>
                        <uicontrol>IPA Lookup</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade> menu item. Otherwise, type or use the <uicontrol>IPA
                        Map</uicontrol> to enter the <i>IPA Target</i> and <i>IPA Actual</i>
                    transcriptions into the fields with the same name. </cmd>
                <stepresult>If you use <uicontrol>IPA Lookup</uicontrol>, a new view will appear
                    with two tabs: <uicontrol>Record Lookup</uicontrol> and
                        <uicontrol>Console</uicontrol>. <uicontrol>Record Lookup</uicontrol> is
                    focused by default.<note>To change dictionary language, click on the
                            <uicontrol>IPA Dictionary</uicontrol> menu in the <wintitle>IPA
                            Lookup</wintitle> view and select desired dictionary (listed by
                        ISO-639-3 Language Code, see <xref href="InputSessionLanguage.xml"/> for
                        instructions for viewing the codes list). Language preferences may also be
                        changed in the <wintitle>Preferences</wintitle> dialog.</note></stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>In <uicontrol>Record Lookup</uicontrol>, choose whether to
                        <uicontrol>Overwrite</uicontrol> existing transcriptions, and select whether
                    to transcribe <uicontrol>IPA Target</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>IPA
                        Actual</uicontrol> by clicking on the check boxes.</cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol> to the right of the utterance in
                        <uicontrol>Record Lookup</uicontrol> to transcribe the record as shown, or
                    click the <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol> button next to an individual group to
                    transcribe only that group.</cmd>
                <stepresult>The selected transcription will appear in the <i>IPA Target</i> and/or
                        <i>IPA Actual</i> tiers.<note>If there is more than one transcription
                        available in the selected dictionary for a word, there will be multiple
                        entried listed in the <uicontrol>Record Lookup</uicontrol>. Select the
                        desired transcription by clicking on it before you
                            <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol> the group or utterance.</note>
                    <image placement="break" scale="30" href="../../images/IPALookup.png"
                        id="image_wdr_vlm_sc"/></stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>You may further modify any transcriptions in the <i>IPA Target</i> and <i>IPA
                        Actual</i> fields by typing or using the <uicontrol>IPA
                    Map</uicontrol>.</cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
