<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_5gx_xgz_ff">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <body>
    <p> Phon is a software program that greatly facilitates a number of tasks related to the
      analysis of transcript-based and acoustically-measured speech data. Built to support research
      in phonological development (including babbling), second language acquisition, and
      phonological disorders, Phon can also be used for virtually all types of phonological
      investigations (e.g. loanword phonology, fieldwork in phonology, sociolinguistic studies).
      Phon supports multimedia data linkage, unit segmentation (e.g. utterance, word),
      multiple-blind transcription, automatic labeling of data (features, syllabification), and
      systematic comparisons between target (model) and actual (produced) phonological forms. Phon
      is also equipped with many facilities for data analysis, including query methods for phonology
      (e.g. phones, features, syllables, …) as well as acoustic data. </p>
    <p>Version 2 of Phon brings together two of the most important areas of empirical investigation
      in the are of child phonology, as it integrates transcript-based analyses of phonological data
      with the facilities for acoustic analysis provided by Praat. With this new version of Phon,
      and in addition to the functions listed above, the user can now: </p>
    <ul id="ul_fdf_2v1_5p">
      <li>Import existing TextGrids into Phon sessions </li>
      <li>Generate TextGrids from existing Phon records </li>
      <li>Visualize TextGrids directly into Phon </li>
      <li>Send TextGrids to Praat for editing in a single click </li>
      <li>Run speech analysis functions directly from the Phon Query menu </li>
      <li>Export speech measurement data for further analysis </li>
    </ul>
    <p>All of these functions are accessible through a user-friendly graphical interface. Databases
      managed within Phon can also be queried using a powerful search system adapted for the needs
      of the phonologist. This software program works on Mac OS X, Windows and Linux platforms and
      is compliant with the CHILDES (<xref href="http://talkbank.org/" format="html"
        scope="external">​TalkBank</xref>) XML data format. Phon is being made freely available to
      the community as open-source software. Phon facilitates data exchange among researchers and is
      currently used for the elaboration of the shared <xref href="http://childes.psy.cmu.edu/phon/"
        format="html" scope="external">​PhonBank</xref> database, designed to support empirical
      needs of research in all areas of phonology and phonological development.</p>
    <p>Current development of Phon and PhonBank is supported by the National Institute of Health.
      Earlier development of Phon was funded by grants from National Science Foundation, Canada Fund
      for Innovation, Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada, Petro-Canada Fund
      for Young Innovators, and the Office of the Vice-President (Research) and the Faculty of Arts
      at Memorial University of Newfoundland. </p>
    <p>While it is impossible to name everyone who ended up being involved in one way or another in
      this project, we owe special thanks to a wonderful group of early adopters and beta testers,
      students and researchers alike, without whom it would have been much more difficult to produce
      the current software program. We are also grateful to Paul Boersma for this tremendous
      collaboration toward the interactions between Praat and related functions within Phon 2. </p>
  </body>
</topic>
