<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="taskId">
    <title>Generate Report</title>
    <shortdesc>Generate a report from query results, in CSV format.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>From a <uicontrol>Query</uicontrol> tab in the <wintitle>Query Project</wintitle>
            window, or from the <wintitle>Query History</wintitle> window with a query
            selected:</context>
        <steps id="steps_ffx_3zx_q2">
            <step>
                <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Report</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
                <stepresult>This will generate the <wintitle>Report</wintitle> window, with a tab
                    for <uicontrol>Report Format</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Result
                    Sets</uicontrol>.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Report Format</uicontrol> tab, specify <uicontrol>Report
                        Sections</uicontrol> in the <uicontrol>Report Outline</uicontrol> field on
                    the left, and edit options for each section in the fields on the right,
                    according to <xref id="6593" href="../../report/concepts/AboutReportOutline.xml"/>.</cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Select the <wintitle>Results Sets</wintitle> tab at the top of the
                    window.</cmd>
                <stepresult>A list of the searches performed during the query will be displayed,
                    with the <i>Session</i> name and <i># of Results</i> for each set. This list may
                    take a moment to generate fully. To change display options for this list, click
                    on the menu button to the right of the column headings.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Select the <i>Result Sets</i> you would like to report on by clicking the check
                    box to the left of each <i>Result Set</i>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>
                    <note>By default, all <i>Result Sets</i> are selected. You may
                            <uicontrol>Deselect all</uicontrol> result sets or <uicontrol>Hide empty
                            result sets</uicontrol> by using the check boxes.</note>
                </stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>If you do not wish to generate a report at this time, click
                        <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol>. To continue generating, click <uicontrol>Save
                        Report...</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>A <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> dialog will appear.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Specify a file name and destination directory for your report file and click
                        <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>, or click <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> to
                    return to the <wintitle>Report</wintitle> window without generating a
                    report.</cmd>
                <stepresult>Once you click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>, the report will be written
                    to the specified directory and will open in your system's default editor for CSV
                        files.<note>To prevent future reports from opening as soon as they are
                        generated, deselect the <uicontrol>Open report when done</uicontrol>
                        option.</note></stepresult>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
    
</task>
