<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="taskId">
    <title>Derive Session</title>
    <shortdesc>Derive a new session using records from existing sessions.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>From the <wintitle>Project Manager</wintitle> window:</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Choose the <menucascade>
                        <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol>
                        <uicontrol>Derive Session...</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade> menu item.</cmd>
                <stepresult>A <wintitle>Merge Sessions</wintitle> dialog will appear.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Enter a <uicontrol>Session name</uicontrol> and Destination <uicontrol
                        >Corpus</uicontrol> in the provided fields. Select one or more of the
                    sessions for the split or merge and click <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>The second page of the <wintitle>Merge Sessions</wintitle> dialog will
                        appear.<note>If you chose only one session, the selected records will be put
                        into the new session. If you select more than one session, the selected
                        records will be merged into a new session.</note></stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Select a session from the <uicontrol>Session</uicontrol> list at the left and
                    choose whether to merge or split <uicontrol>All records</uicontrol>, a subset of
                        <uicontrol>Specific records</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Records for
                        participant(s)</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Records from Search
                        results</uicontrol>. Repeat this process for all sessions in the
                        <uicontrol>Session</uicontrol> list. Click
                    <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>This will begin the merging of the selected records/sessions.<note>If
                        you choose to merge only specific records, you will have to specify the
                        relevant record numbers. To specify several individual records, separate
                        them with a comma and a space. To specify a range, separate the beginning
                        and end record numbers with two periods and a space. If you choose to merge
                        records for specific participants, you must select the participants from the
                        list. If you choose to merge records from search results, you must select a
                        past search from the list.</note></stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Once the <i>Session Merger shutdown</i> alert appears, click
                        <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>The newly derived session will appear in the specified
                        <uicontrol>Corpus</uicontrol> in the <wintitle>Project Manager</wintitle>. </stepresult>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
