<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="taskId">
    <title>Query Project</title>
    <shortdesc>Run a query for patterns across sessions in a project.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>From the <wintitle>Project Manager</wintitle> or <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle>
                window:</context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Query</uicontrol> menu, select the type of query you would
                    like to perform.</cmd>
                <stepresult>This action generates a <wintitle>Query Project</wintitle>
                    window.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Use the check boxes to select the entire project, one or more corpora, or one
                    or more sessions for the query. From the available panels select options for
                    your search as per the descriptions in the <uicontrol>Query Types</uicontrol>
                    section of the user manual.</cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Choose whether to <uicontrol>Include excluded records</uicontrol> by selecting
                    or deselecting that check box, and click the <uicontrol>Run Query</uicontrol>
                    button.</cmd>
                <stepresult>This action will generate a <wintitle>Results</wintitle> tab, which
                    calculates the number of results for each search and list the sessions searched;
                    this is referred to as a <i>Result Set</i>. <note>To toggle between editing your
                        script as a form or as a script, click the <uicontrol>Toggle
                            script/form</uicontrol> button at the bottom right corner of the
                        query.</note>
                </stepresult>
            </step>
            <step><cmd>To view an individual <i>Result Set</i>, double-click on it in the
                <wintitle>Results</wintitle> tab. </cmd><stepresult>A session will open with a <wintitle>Results</wintitle> window next to it. <note>To show
                        only <i>Result Sets</i> with more than zero results, select <uicontrol>Hide
                            empty result sets</uicontrol>. For further instructions on using the
                            <wintitle>Results</wintitle> window, see <xref id="5648"
                            href="ViewResultSet.xml"/></note></stepresult></step> 
            
            
            <step>
                <cmd>To view your search results in your <wintitle>Query History</wintitle> later,
                    you must save them. To do so, click <uicontrol>Save results</uicontrol>. Enter a
                    name for your results, choose whether or not the results should be
                        <i>Starred</i>, enter any desired comments and click
                        <uicontrol>Ok</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>The search will be saved inside the project folder, in the
                        '<i>__search</i>' directory, and can now be viewed using the <wintitle>Query
                        History</wintitle> window.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To get a detailed report of the results, click the
                        <uicontrol>Report</uicontrol> button at the top of the
                        <wintitle>Results</wintitle> tab.</cmd>
                <stepresult>
                    <note>To merge all records with results into a single session, see <xref
                            id="0124" href="../projman/tasks/DeriveSession.xml"/>.</note>
                </stepresult>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
