<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="taskId">
    <title>Export to CSV file(s)</title>
    <shortdesc>Export <i>Phon</i> sessions as CSV (comma-separated values) files.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>The CSV export module can export Phon sessions into a specified folder as UTF-8
                encoded CSV files.</p>
            <p>From the <uicontrol>Project Manager</uicontrol> window:</p>
        </context>
        <steps id="steps_3fbd2bb6-677b-4d56-b099-694f006388f9">
            <step>
                <cmd>Select the <menucascade>
                        <uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol>
                        <uicontrol>Export to CSV...</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade> menu item.</cmd>
                <stepresult>This action will generate a <uicontrol>CSV Export</uicontrol>
                    window.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To select the destination folder for the export, click the <uicontrol>Browse
                        for folder...</uicontrol> button to the right of the <uicontrol>Destination
                        folder</uicontrol> field, locate the desired folder and click
                        <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>. Select the sessions you would like to export
                    using the check boxes at the left of the <uicontrol>Sessions</uicontrol> list.
                    Click the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
                <stepresult>This action will prompt you to set up columns for the
                    export.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd> To add a column to the export, type its name in the provided field and press
                        <userinput>Enter</userinput> or click <uicontrol>Add column/+</uicontrol>.
                    To remove a tier from the list, select it and click the <uicontrol>Remove
                        Column/-</uicontrol> button. To export a tier which is not available in the
                    existing list, type <b>"</b><userinput>Tier:&lt;tier name></userinput><b>"</b>
                    in the provided field and click the <uicontrol>Add Column/+</uicontrol> or press
                        <userinput>Enter</userinput>. Click on any tier name in the list and use the
                        <uicontrol>up/down arrow</uicontrol> buttons to change the column ordering.
                    Click the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
                <info/>
                <stepresult>This action will activate the export.<note>The default column list for
                        export includes: Session Name, Record #, and all default <i>Phon</i> tiers.
                        The default can be restored by using the <uicontrol>Reset to
                            default</uicontrol> button on the bottom right corner of the column
                        list. This list of columns is saved after export and re-loaded the next time
                        CSV export is opened.</note><note>To export blind user transcriptions, add
                        the tier "<userinput>IPA [Target|Actual] (&lt;username>)</userinput>" (e.g.
                        Tier:IPA Target (JSmith)).</note></stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Once the <i>Export complete</i> alert appears at the bottom of the
                        <uicontrol>CSV Export</uicontrol> window, click the
                        <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol> button. </cmd>
                <stepresult>Session files for all corpora in the exported project will appear in the
                    chosen directory with the format <i>Corpus name-Session
                    name.csv</i>.</stepresult>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
