<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="conceptId">
    <title>About Syllabification</title>
    <conbody>
        <p>In the <wintitle>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</wintitle> view, the syllable position
            for each phone in <i>IPA Target</i> and <i>IPA Actual</i> is displayed.</p>
        <p>A number of syllable positions are available, including appendices, onsets, nuclei and
            codas. Each different phone position is displayed in a distinct color.</p>
        <p>Syllabification plays a role in <i>Phon</i> Queries; it allows a user to search for a
            phone in a specific syllable position. For example, phonetic or phonological processes
            which only occur in onsets may be observed by focusing specifically on consonants in
            onset positions.</p>
        <p><i>Phon</i> will automatically syllabify transcriptions in the <i>IPA Target</i> and
                <i>IPA Actual</i> tiers, using any one of its built-in syllable templates (based on
            syllable structure of the following languages):</p>
        <p>
            <ul id="ul_yww_cuh_vc">
                <li>Berber</li>
                <li>Catalan</li>
                <li>Cree</li>
                <li>Dutch</li>
                <li>English</li>
                <li>French</li>
                <li>Gurindji</li>
                <li>Italian</li>
                <li>Portuguese (European)</li>
                <li>Spanish</li>
                <li>Vietnamese</li>
            </ul>
        </p>
        <p>The syllabifier language for a project can be chosen from the
                <wintitle>Preferences</wintitle> dialog. Also, the syllabifier for an individual
            record my be changed by right-clicking (<userinput>CTRL+click</userinput>) on that
            record's <i>Target Syllables</i> or <i>Actual Syllables</i> in the
                <wintitle>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</wintitle> view and choosing
                <uicontrol>Syllabify with</uicontrol> > <uicontrol>&lt;Language name></uicontrol>
            (the current default syllabifier is highlighted in bold in this menu).</p>
        <note>When faced with irregular utterances or transcriptions, <i>Phon</i> may make errors in
            syllabification. It is important to perform a visual verification of the syllabification
            of transcriptions in your project in order to ensure that Queries including
            syllabification information will return accurate results.</note>
    </conbody>
</concept>
