<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="conceptId">
    <title>About Media</title>
    <conbody>
        <p>Sessions in <i>Phon</i> usually consist of a media recording (either audio or video)
            coupled with transcriptions of utterances from the recording and separated into
                <i>Records</i>. Each <i>Record</i> can be associated via a process called
            segmentation to the time in the recording during which the utterance occurred.</p>
        <p>To facilitate the segmentation and transcription of media files, <i>Phon</i> has a
            built-in media player. This player is available in the <wintitle>Media Player</wintitle>
            view. To use the media player, you must first have a media file linked to your session
            (see <xref href="LinkMedia.xml"/> for instructions).</p>
        <p><b>Basic Media functions:</b>
            <ul>
                <li><b>Play</b><p>To play your media, click the play button in the <wintitle>Media
                            Player</wintitle> view.</p></li>
                <li><b>Volume and Muting</b><p>To change the volume of playback, click the
                            <uicontrol>Volume</uicontrol> button to the right of the media progress
                        slider, move the volume slider to the desired level (or click the
                            <uicontrol>Toggle mute</uicontrol> button) and then click away from the
                        volume area. </p></li>
                <li><b>Jump playback to another time</b><p>To change playback time, click on the
                        desired position on the media progress slider. To jump to a specific
                        playback time see <xref href="GoTo.xml">.</xref></p></li>
            </ul> Other media-related functions include creating and exporting media segments,
            adjusting segment times, viewing a waveform of a segment's audio, and taking snapshots
            of your media.</p>
    </conbody>
</concept>
