<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="conceptId">
    <title>About Export Methods</title>
    <conbody>
        <p>The export functions in the <wintitle>Media Player</wintitle> and the
                <wintitle>Waveform</wintitle> views are fundamentally different. From the
                <wintitle>Media</wintitle> view, exporting saves a portion of a linked video (or
            audio) file in its original format. From the <wintitle>Waveform</wintitle> view,
            exporting saves a portion of a WAVE file which is generated from the original media, but
            is separate from it.</p>
        <p>Since the two export functions operate on different media types (usually video vs.
            audio), they have different behaviour.</p>
        <p>Crucially, exporting media segments from the <wintitle>Media Player</wintitle> view may
            cause <i>clipping</i>; that is, a small portion of your segment may be excluded from the
            export. This is because this export operates on a video file, in which each video frame
            is associated with a certain time interval. <i>Phon</i> does not export video frames in
            parts; if the start or end time of a media segment falls in the middle of a frame's time
            interval, then that frame will be excluded from the export. This may occur even if you
            choose to extract only the audio portion of a segment from the <wintitle>Media
                Player</wintitle> view.</p>
        <p>To export audio segments for analysis without any clipping, it is best to export them
            from the <wintitle>Waveform</wintitle> view. When you first open this view after you
            have linked media to your session, you will be prompted to create a WAVE file from your
            media. It is this audio-only file from which the <wintitle>Waveform</wintitle> view
            extracts segments, thus avoiding clipping.</p>
    </conbody>
</concept>
