<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="taskId">
    <title>Segment Media</title>
    <shortdesc>Segment media into records.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>With the <wintitle>Media Player</wintitle> and <wintitle>Segmentation</wintitle>
                views open:</context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Play</uicontrol> button in the <wintitle>Media
                        Player</wintitle>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>
                    This will begin playback of the media file.
                </stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>From the <wintitle>Segmentation</wintitle> view, create a new segment by
                    clicking on the <uicontrol>&lt;no speaker></uicontrol> option or the appropriate
                    participant's name in the <uicontrol>Participants</uicontrol> field. Alternately
                    you may type <userinput>CMD/CTRL+0</userinput> for an unspecified participant,
                    or <userinput>CMD/CTRL+1</userinput>, <userinput>CMD/CTRL+2</userinput>, etc.
                    for a particular participant as noted to the left of his/her name in the list. </cmd>
                <stepresult>When the default segment length is set to 3000 ms, your segment will end
                    when you either click on the participants name or use the specified keystrokes.
                    The segment will begin 3 seconds before that action. The media file will
                    continue to play.<note>You may want to adjust the default segment length value
                        depending on the nature of your study. Simply type in the desired segment
                        length (in milliseconds) in the <uicontrol>Segment Window</uicontrol> field.
                        A segment window of 0 will make the segment length unlimited; each segment
                        will begin at the endpoint of the previous segment.</note><note>The
                            <uicontrol>Current Window</uicontrol> values display the beginning and
                        end time of your segment. The second value always represents the current
                        playback time. The first value represents the beginning of your segment;
                        when in blue this time also corresponds to the end of the previous segment.
                        Clicking this value when it is blue causes the program to ignore the
                        endpoint of the previous segment and change to a segment beginning point
                        appropriate for the <uicontrol>Segment Window</uicontrol>
                    value.</note></stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Repeat Step 2 after each utterance until the entire media file has been
                    segmented.</cmd>
                <stepresult>By default, this action generates a new record in the <wintitle>Session
                        Editor</wintitle> for each segmented media clip and places the new record
                    after the current one.<note>You may instead choose to insert the new record at
                        the end of the session by selecting <uicontrol>Insert record at end of
                            session</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>Mode</uicontrol> combo box. You
                        may also choose to overwrite the segment for an individual record, if for
                        example you accidentally cut off the end of an utterance. To do so, select
                            <uicontrol>Replace segment for current record</uicontrol> from the
                            <uicontrol>Mode</uicontrol> combo box, and create a new segment with the
                        desired endpoint following Step 2.</note><note>To resume segmentation from a
                        certain time, click the arrow at the bottom right of the <wintitle>Media
                            Player</wintitle>. This will open a context menu with several options.
                            <uicontrol>Go to...</uicontrol> allows you to input a specific time for
                        the player to jump to, <uicontrol>Go to end of segmented media</uicontrol>
                        brings you to the end of your last segment, and <uicontrol>Go to end of last
                            segment for &lt;Participant></uicontrol> brings you to the end of the
                        last segmented utterance by the specified participant.</note>
                    <image placement="break" scale="30" href="../images/SegmentGoTo.png"
                        id="image_wdr_vlm_sc"/></stepresult>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
