<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="syllabification--alignment">
    <title>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</title>
    <body>
        <p>In the <wintitle>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</wintitle> view, the syllable position
            for each phone in <i>IPA Target</i> and <i>IPA Actual</i> is displayed along with the <keyword>phone alignment</keyword>.</p>
        <fig id="fig_gvd_4qs_dld">
            <title>Syllabification &amp; Alignment View</title>
            <image placement="inline" href="images/syllabification_and_alignment_view.png"
                id="image_hvd_4qs_dld">
                <alt>Syllabification &amp; Alignment View</alt>
            </image>
        </fig>
    </body>
        
    <topic id="syllabification">
        <title>Syllabification</title>
        <body>
            <p>A number of syllable positions are available, including appendices, onsets, nuclei and
                    codas. Each different phone position is displayed in a distinct color.</p>
            <p>Syllabification plays a role in <i>Phon</i> Queries; it allows a user to search for a
                phone in a specific syllable position. For example, phonetic or phonological processes
                which only occur in onsets may be observed by focusing specifically on consonants in
                onset positions.</p>
            <p><i>Phon</i> will automatically syllabify transcriptions in the <i>IPA Target</i> and
                <i>IPA Actual</i> tiers, using any one of its built-in syllable templates (based on
                syllable structure of the following languages):</p>
            <p>
                <ul id="ul_yww_cuh_vc">
                    <li>Berber</li>
                    <li>Catalan</li>
                    <li>Cree</li>
                    <li>Dutch</li>
                    <li>English</li>
                    <li>French</li>
                    <li>Gurindji</li>
                    <li>Italian</li>
                    <li>Portuguese (European)</li>
                    <li>Spanish</li>
                    <li>Vietnamese</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>The syllabifier language for a project can be chosen from the
                <wintitle>Preferences</wintitle> dialog. Also, the syllabifier for an individual
                record my be changed by right-clicking (<userinput>CTRL+click</userinput>) on that
                record's <i>Target Syllables</i> or <i>Actual Syllables</i> in the
                <wintitle>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</wintitle> view and choosing
                <uicontrol>Syllabify with</uicontrol> > <uicontrol>&lt;Language name></uicontrol>
                (the current default syllabifier is highlighted in bold in this menu).</p>
            <note>When faced with irregular utterances or transcriptions, <i>Phon</i> may make errors in
                syllabification. It is important to perform a visual verification of the syllabification
                of transcriptions in your project in order to ensure that Queries including
                syllabification information will return accurate results.</note>
        </body>
    
        <topic id="modify_syllabification">
            <title>Modify Syllabification</title>
            <shortdesc>Check to ensure proper syllabification of <i>IPA Target</i> and <i>IPA Actual</i>
                phones.</shortdesc>
            <body>
                <section>In order for the Syllabification module to work, the <i>IPA Target</i> and/or <i
                    >IPA Actual</i> transcriptions must be completed (verified in the case of blind
                    transcriptions) and saved. From the <wintitle>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</wintitle>
                    view:</section>
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <p>Visually observe the syllabification for each record to determine whether
                            phones are properly syllabified in the <i>Target Syllables</i> and/or <i>Actual
                                Syllables</i> tier(s).</p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>Right click (<userinput>CTRL+click</userinput>) on any phone which appears to
                            be improperly syllabified and select the proper syllable constituent from the
                            context menu. Alternately, select the phone in question and type the character
                            underlined in the list below for the proper syllable constituent.</p>
                        <itemgroup>
                            <ul>
                                <li><u>L</u>eft Appendix</li>
                                <li><u>O</u>nset</li>
                                <li><u>N</u>ucleus</li>
                                <li><u>C</u>oda</li>
                                <li><u>R</u>ight Appendix</li>
                                <li>O<u>E</u>HS (Onset of an Empty-Headed Syllable)</li>
                                <li><u>A</u>mbisyllabic</li>
                                <li><u>U</u>nknown</li>
                            </ul>
                            <note>When a transcription contains a sequence of two or more vowels in a row,
                                the Toggle <u>H</u>iatus option becomes available.
                                This allows the vowels to be either included in the same or separate
                                nuclei.</note>
                        </itemgroup>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
    </topic>

    <topic id="alignment">
        <title>Alignment</title>
        <body>
            <p>Displayed in the <wintitle>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</wintitle> view, the
                <uicontrol>Alignment</uicontrol> tier allows a comparison to be made between target
                (model) forms of utterances and their actual (spoken) realizations.</p>
            <p>Alignment is visualized in <i>Phon</i> as an arrangment of transcribed phones from <i>IPA
                Actual</i> lined up underneath phones from <i>IPA Target</i>. <i>Phon</i> makes a
                comparison between the number, order, and features of target phones and actual phones,
                in order to determine what phonetic information may have been lost, retained, or added
                in production.<note>To include syllabification visualization in the <i>Alignment</i>
                    tier, select <uicontrol>Color in alignment</uicontrol> in the
                    <wintitle>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</wintitle> view.</note></p>
            <image placement="break"
                href="./images/alignment.png" id="image_wdr_vlm_sc"/>
            <p>This comparison is important for a number of query scripts in <i>Phon</i>, such as
                <wintitle>Phones</wintitle>, <wintitle>Metathesis</wintitle>, and
                <wintitle>Harmony</wintitle>. These queries require information from both the <i>IPA
                    Target</i> and <i>IPA Actual</i> tiers, and how the two tiers relate.</p>
            <note>When faced with irregular utterances or transcriptions, <i>Phon</i> may make
                errors in alignment. It is important to perform a visual verification of the alignment
                of transcriptions in your project in order to ensure that queries including alignment
                information will return accurate results.</note>
        </body>
        
        <topic id="modify_alignment">
            <title>Modify Alignment</title>
            <shortdesc>Check to ensure proper alignment between <i>IPA Target</i> and <i>IPA Actual</i>
                phones.</shortdesc>
            <body>
                <section>In order for the Alignment module to work, the <i>IPA Target</i> and/or <i>IPA
                    Actual</i> transcriptions must be completed (verified in the case of blind
                    transcriptions) and saved. From the <wintitle>Syllabification &amp;
                        Alignment</wintitle> view:</section>
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <p>Select any phone in the <i>Alignment</i> tier which does not appear to be
                            properly aligned.</p>
                        <itemgroup>An outline will appear around the phone in question.</itemgroup>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>Use <userinput>OPT/ALT+left/right arrows</userinput> to move the phone into
                            proper alignment. Alternately, click and drag a phone to re-align it.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>Use <userinput>OPT/ALT+up/down arrows</userinput> to alternate phone selection
                            between Target phones and Actual phones. Repeat Step 2 until all phones are
                            aligned to your satisfaction.</p>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
        
    </topic>

</topic>
