<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="conceptId">
    <title>About Editor Views</title>
    <shortdesc>Information in each session is displayed in a series of small windows within the
            <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle>, called views. There are several types of
        views:</shortdesc>
    <body>
        <ol>
            <li>Views with access/reference to the entire session:<ul id="ul_edd_xdk_rc">
                <li><wintitle>Session Information</wintitle></li>
                <li><wintitle>Tier Management</wintitle></li>
            </ul></li>
            <li>Views with information relating to individual records:<ul id="ul_mjk_bek_rc">
                <li><wintitle>Record Data</wintitle></li>
                <li><wintitle>Syllabification &amp; Alignment</wintitle></li>
                <li><wintitle>IPA Validation</wintitle></li>
            </ul></li>
            <li>Views with media functions:<ul id="ul_mrf_itk_rc">
                <li><wintitle>Media Player</wintitle></li>
                    <li><wintitle>Speech Analysis</wintitle> (formally
                            <uicontrol>Waveform</uicontrol>)</li>
                <li><wintitle>Segmentation</wintitle></li>
            </ul></li>
            <li>Views that allow you to search for text within a session:<ul id="ul_mrf_bek_rc">
                <li><wintitle>Find &amp; Replace</wintitle></li>
            </ul></li>
            <li>Utility views which help with IPA transcription:<ul id="ul_xqc_gek_rc">
                    <li><wintitle>IPA Lookup</wintitle></li>
                </ul></li>
        </ol>
        <p> To open a view, select it from the <uicontrol>View</uicontrol> menu. Functions for open
            views are available both within the views themselves, and in the
                <uicontrol>View</uicontrol> menu. To close a view, click the
                <uicontrol>Close/X</uicontrol> in the top right corner of that viewor choose the <menucascade>
                <uicontrol>View</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol>&lt;view title></uicontrol>
                <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> menu selection.</p>
        <p>Not all views must be open at any given time, and views may be moved around within the
                <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> or "undocked" as their own separate window. </p>
        <p>Views retain their currently defined size and position each time you exit
            <i>Phon</i>.</p>
    </body>
    <topic id="view_actions">
        <title>General View Actions</title>
        <body>
            <p>The following actions are available to all editor views.</p>
        </body>
        <topic id="maximize_view">
            <title>Maximize View</title>
            <shortdesc>Maximize a view within the Session Editor window.</shortdesc>
            <body>
                <section>From the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> or an undocked view:</section>
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <p>Click the maximize button near the top right corner of the view you wish to
                            maximize, or when the view is focused, press
                            <userinput>CTRL+M</userinput>.</p>
                        <itemgroup>If the view was docked, it will expand to fill the <wintitle>Session
                            Editor</wintitle> window. If the view was undocked, it will expand to fill
                            your computer screen.
                            <image placement="break" scale="30"
                                href="../../images/MaximizeView.png" id="image_wdr_vlm_sc"/></itemgroup>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>To restore the view to its previous size, click the restore button near the top
                            right corner (this button looks like two windows), or press
                            <userinput>CTRL+N</userinput> when the view is in focus.</p>
                        <itemgroup>The view will return to its previous unmaximized position.</itemgroup>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="minimize_view">
            <title>Minimize View</title>
            <shortdesc>Minimize a view within the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> window.</shortdesc>
            <body>
                <section>From the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> or an undocked view:</section>
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <p>Click the <uicontrol>minimize/_</uicontrol> button near the top right corner of
                            the view.</p>
                        <itemgroup>A small title bar for that view will appear at an edge of the
                            <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle>. <image placement="break" scale="30"
                                href="../../images/MinimizeView.png" id="image_wdr_vlm_sc1"/></itemgroup>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>To make a minimized view temporarily reappear, click on its name or icon.</p>
                        <itemgroup>When the focus is changed to another view (i.e. another view is
                            selected), the view will return to its minimized position. <note>To make the
                                view retain its opened position when focus is lost, click the thumbtack
                                button near the top right corner of the title bar. To deactivate this
                                option, click the thumbtack again.</note></itemgroup>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>To restore the minimized view to a normal position within the <wintitle>Session
                            Editor</wintitle> frame, click the restore button near the top right corner
                            (this button looks like two windows), or press <userinput>CTRL+N</userinput>
                            when the view is in focus.</p>
                        <itemgroup>The view will return to its previous docked position in the
                            <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle>, even if it was undocked when you
                            minimized it.</itemgroup>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="relocate_view">
            <title>Relocate View</title>
            <shortdesc>Move a view to a new position within the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle>. </shortdesc>
            <body>
                <section>From the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> window:</section>
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <p>Click on the view's title bar and drag it to the desired location within the
                            <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> window.</p>
                        <itemgroup>As you drag the view, the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> will show
                            the alternate position of that view. When it appears as you wish, release the
                            mouse button. <image placement="break" scale="30"
                                href="../../images/RelocateView.png" id="image_wdr_vlm_sc"/></itemgroup>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>Two or more views may occupy the same location in the <wintitle>Session
                            Editor</wintitle>. To do so, drag and drop one view to the title bar of the
                            other view.</p>
                        <itemgroup>You can switch between views in the same position by selecting the 
                            appropriate tab at the bottom of either view.</itemgroup>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="dock_view">
            <title>Dock View</title>
            <shortdesc>Return an undocked view to the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> window. </shortdesc>
            <body>
                <section>From the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> window, with a view
                    undocked:</section>
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <p>In the top right corner of the view, click the button that looks like a window
                            with an inward arrow (on mouseover it will say <uicontrol>Connects this panel
                                with the frame</uicontrol>). Alternately, select the title bar of the view
                            and press <userinput>CTRL+N</userinput>.<image placement="break" scale="40"
                                href="../../images/DockView.png" id="image_wdr_vlm_sc"/></p>
                        <itemgroup>The view will reappear in the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> window
                            in its previous docked position.<note> You may also click and drag the view's
                                title bar to return it to the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> window in
                                a different position.</note></itemgroup>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="undock_view">
            <title>Undock View</title>
            <shortdesc>Disconnect or "undock" a view from the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle>, making it
                its own separate window.</shortdesc>
            <body>
                <section>From the <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle> window, with the view you wish to
                    undock open:</section>
                <ol>
                    <li>
                        <p>In the top right corner of the view, click the button that looks like a window
                            with an outward arrow (on mouseover it will say <uicontrol>Disconnects this
                                panel from the frame</uicontrol>). Alternately, select the title bar of the
                            view and press <userinput>CTRL+E</userinput>.<image placement="break" scale="30"
                                href="../../images/UndockView.png" id="image_wdr_vlm_sc"/></p>
                        <itemgroup>The view will appear as a separate window in front of the
                            <wintitle>Session Editor</wintitle>.</itemgroup>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>To move the view while it is undocked, click and drag on the small bar centred
                            above the title bar. To resize the view, click and drag on any other edge or
                            corner.</p>
                        <itemgroup>The view will retain its undocked size and position when you exit and
                            reopen <i>Phon</i>.</itemgroup>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
    </topic>
    
</topic>
