<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="taskId">
    <title>Export Results as CSV</title>
    <shortdesc>Create a CSV file from Result Sets generated in a Query.</shortdesc>
    <taskbody>
        <context>From the <wintitle>Query Project</wintitle> window with a <wintitle>Query
        Tab</wintitle> open:</context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Report</uicontrol> button at the top of the numbered
                        <wintitle>Query Tab</wintitle>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>The <wintitle>Report Wizard</wintitle> will appear.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Choose <uicontrol>Export results as CSV</uicontrol> and click
                        <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>The <wintitle>Report Wizard</wintitle> will prompt you to specify
                    options for your CSV report.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Enter a <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> location by clicking the
                        <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol> button to the right of the <uicontrol>Save
                        location</uicontrol> field, locating an appropriate directory, and clicking
                        <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol>.</cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Choose whether to <uicontrol>Export all searches to single file</uicontrol>.
                    This allows you to include the results from separate sessions in the same file.
                    Then, choose the sessions whose search results you would like to export and
                    click <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>The <wintitle>Report Wizard</wintitle> will prompt you to setup the
                    columns for your CSV export.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To reorder tiers, select the column you would like to re-order and use the
                        <userinput>up/down arrows</userinput> to rearrange it. To add a column, type
                    its name in the provided field following instructions in the <wintitle>Report
                        Wizard</wintitle> window and click <uicontrol>Add column/+</uicontrol>. To
                    remove an unneccessary column from the export, select the column name and click
                        <uicontrol>Remove column/-</uicontrol>. To choose the default column
                    arrangement, click the <uicontrol>Reset to default</uicontrol> button at the
                    bottom right corner of the <wintitle>Report Wizard</wintitle>. When you are
                    satisfied with your column settings, click <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <stepresult>Your report(s) will be generated in the specified save
                    location.</stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To open your report, click its name in the <wintitle>Report Wizard</wintitle>.
                    Otherwise, click <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol> to close the <wintitle>Report
                        Wizard</wintitle>.</cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>        